Welcome to
the Return, you can show the sixteenth Imu, you
can show it to the guys. This is a
person who prays, as I already
mentioned,
we begin a
conversation about the prayers that we will
offer to the team of bu medicine, 7 s to 7 s, pono
budam, seven traditional
ishani, this is
how he is the manager of this
group, he is their
manager. So, we will have such a new
Sana, such an
emphasis, you need to include yourself in
prayers, this is the Sun, this is a small change,
instead of
praying for the whole
world, practically. I
remember when when you
graduate, you have to write a
term paper,
one after a bachelor's degree, then after a
master's degree, I wrote, I
wrote my thesis, this is a
famous Buddhist teacher, a Buddhist
scholar, I wrote something about his
book and the perfection of giving.
And then you have to write a dissertation,
defend your thesis, and your
professors ask you, interrogate you,
it's very scary, you go to their office
and there are three professors from
your faculty, they ask you questions
about your thesis. When I
had my defense, I still
remember the main question that they
asked me. When you do these prayers.  In
Buddhism, you pray for
yourself when you pray for all living
beings, it includes
you.
Yes, indeed, I am one of
these living beings and the garden is not the fifth
Dalai Lama. When you pray for all
living beings, you are you, you are aware that this
includes that one of them, you are the most
important of them, no, you are the most, the least
important, you are equal with others, and
this is a refreshing
thought.
This photo was meant to remind that
when you pray to the
Medicine Buddha in your meditations, and Tim
said that you have
this, you want during
retreat. Don't forget that when you
pray for all living
beings, there is one in the room
and equal relationships, equal time for
this for yourself, it is easy to forget about this, it is
typical for people to forget about this. In this Sana,
it is
emphasized that here are also included in
this, this
group, tell Teddy something there, there is
some
note, I'm kidding.
Next,
Ima, this is
order, this is the rest of
Satan. This week, what will we
do? This week, we will be forgotten.
We will
ask for
prayers,
prayers, a new word for na, we will be
this meeting also of all these people. 6,000.
At the stadium, we will do a common
prayer for everyone.
We will do it all the same way. When you
look at the scale, think about
the scale, think about the stadium, as it was in
that video that was shown. Then
we will have special prayers. They are different
for different Buddhas. They
have different ones. We have different
requests, so to speak, for everyone. We
will address the most important ones in
class. You can listen to them in class,
and then you can
do them when you are already
alone. I will now include the teaching
on emptiness here and add A and his most
famous
book, an element of this book of wisdom. This
will help with your garden. When you do
prayers, you perform
each bu, you need to remember
about emptiness.
So, this is a difficult book.
Nagan is a heavy author. That's how he does it so
simply. There is emptiness, it is not easy,
not intuitively, it must be studied and learned.
It is not something that
people
calmly understand and perceive. No one has ever had this happen
to anyone. This needs to be
learned. As you know, we are
learning to ride a bicycle. There was someone
who will
teach you and horseback
exercises
so that we understand emptiness. But this is work
that will need to be done. Well,  You have to work hard
for this, how do we begin? It's
not easy when I couldn't sleep in the
monastery. I read his poetry. I couldn't. I
fell asleep right away. Can you save a lot of money on
insomnia medicine?
Next,
Ima, how am I different from these
Buddhas? Am I different from them, or am I somehow the same?
This is the big
subject of the third section. There is no twenty-
second
section. We are in the twenty-second section,
which is called
the study of
what, the study of someone who has achieved the
goal,
achievement, how many sections are there in total?
27, the twenty-second section, which we are in,
and there is the study of an enlightened
being, what do they look like, what are they made of, how do
they arise? The first question is, how do I
differ from the
enlightened ones, the difference between me and an
enlightened being and a Buddha. Are we
practically the same or are we different? And
we will study this question. Here is
the stanza
next.
I don't like it. There are
original source texts in
Sanskrit. I studied this thanks to the
Tibetan translation that was made.
A thousand years ago,
somewhere. But somehow Sanskrit is
more poetic for
me. This is what
he writes. This is his original spelling
every time I tell you.  I'm giving you some
stanza,
I'll present to you forgiven
Sanskrit, about the English-speaking audience,
cultured, let's say, Sanskrit, I
divided it so that
English-speaking people could pronounce it, then
I'll give you a chance to
pronounce it correctly, and this is in the
second line, you see it in capital letters, it's
written in bold, the first
two are the pronunciation of an ordinary
English-speaking listener, and the second line is
how a person who speaks
Sanskrit would pronounce this, the benefit
you want. If you want to
read them or quote them, please, the
third is
Tibetan. Tibetan
translation is usually
twice as long as
Sanskrit, and I have an English
translation, and it can be three times
longer
than
Sanskrit. Chinese is a very economical
language. English is not like that. I pronounce it for
luck. I will pronounce it for luck
correctly. You can, of course, I will. You
can
read it. They are
not a body or consciousness, they are something
else. They have neither a body nor
consciousness. The one who left is gone, he has
no body or mind of his own. When are they
then? Where are they? Where are they?  Where did they
go and this is a very very typical
text of
Nagar and many, many generations have
misunderstood many, many people have strange
thoughts about these
lines entire generations entire schools of
Buddhism did not understand anything in what he
said made strange
conclusions there is no body or
mind you have to sit there
somewhere far away to retire
oh I want so
[music]
you know even to hide because they
really
misunderstood He is a great writer tea writer of
emptiness in history and he is the most misunderstood
misunderstood writer about the emptiness of
history you need to be taught to
understand what he says what he
says He does not say that you have no
body no mind He does not
say this he does not
mean when you read on
garna this is what I do with my This is
my whole life I
read sva on the site they can ask me what are
you doing I say I read this is a
lifelong task
When you know the key it is not
so difficult then you will find the correct
explanations and in our line of
transmission
he is 100% right he understood
perfectly I do not think that  someone
uh was able to jump over it and
do better this is your transmission line he
transmitted it very carefully very
precisely I I am conducting I brought spent 3
days in class
Sonya three damn days
in class a 1
hour class I am talking about 1214 hours I have not
finished yet I am still working on this
class it is very
deep your book it is
interesting we will see we will discuss on Monday the
topic she writes about the ethics of
guilt among all the books her
book is the oldest 2000 years plus and it is
very
complex 200 plus vows for
Mona and there are many vows different and for form it
took
years maybe we will finish on Monday
evening this
[applause]
[music]
book now on the last
page it is a very deep
book It is a very ancient language as you can
say we read in Chinese
which is 3000
years old we had to use
John Brady's database constantly and among
other
books 50,000
pages of comments
which is John Ready and in one second
we can do a search and we can find
if  We don't understand
vows, for example, you
can't pack spices, it's impossible, it's a
threat. If you see what this does,
the story about
the nuns asked a young
handsome monk to help them
pack some spices, but we don't know
this story. Why
can't you
pack
spices in bags? Every time we saw
such vows and we didn't know the answer, we
found the answers in another
book. It would have been
450 T ago. We looked for something. It's in the
database. We kept returning to the
same book. I then said, "
Let's translate that book."
This is a 30-
year project. This is a very large
commentary from a person who
lived 600 years
ago. I was preparing for the book
because most likely, sleep will start a new
book. I don't know, but it
seems to me that I was
studying all the time. How did we find the
answers? There are answers in that book. There are actually two
books, one is not one, but two
books. The answers we found were in
two different
books, written by the same person with the
same title,
it's not the same book. You see, for 7
years, every time we had a question about a vow,
we looked for it in the
book, we found it.  All the answers are in this
one book, but it turned out that these are two
different books with the same
title.
He
wrote a rewritten book of 8,000 pages and then
rewrote it. You will
translate. What are we going to do
now? In
this line of
transmission, everything is very neat and precise and it is
presented very accurately. I don’t
think you will find this anywhere
else. Of course, people come
to
me, I’m a teacher at the
airport. I’m like, “Yes,
I don’t want to criticize other
traditions.” I don’t want to
do this, but they are
wrong. 90%,
99% are wrong. It’s just like
when they teach you
to repair a car and you break it.
I tried. My
teacher. Here’s my teacher
in
1976. My watch broke and he tells me, “Fix it.”
I don’t know, but you. Can I? Are you not
American? It says “Made in America.”
You can’t fix it? “
Repair it.”
Listen, here it says “Made in
America.” I can’t fix it. It’s not
broken. He said, “Repair the car.” I’ve
never touched a car in my life.
I don’t know anything about cars.
Teach yourself. I  I
learned, I took apart the whole engine. I broke
it and it never worked again.
It
started, maybe worked for one day
and then
broke down.
It broke on the
longest bridge in
America, on the highest bridge. What I'm
trying to say is that it's very similar to the
engine of a car on a
Garn. It's very
deep, it's very
complex, and all the other ways they
read it. This is wrong, this is a
mistake. You'll be on the ridge at night
and you'll be driving a llama from Kennedy Airport, and it will break down in
the middle of a traffic jam at night, and there was a storm.
We tried to start this stupid
car. For now, I want to say that it looks like a Garn. There are some that
he
says 99% of what he tells me. I've never
seen
it explained to me on any show. When you
ask me about when he tells me I
met a teacher at the airport, he looks
very good. I say, "Okay, don't
ask me about the details, don't
ask me if they can teach you
emptiness because they can't.
I say this openly and honestly, they
can't. They, they can be
nice, they can.
Ring a bell in the right place. But
they don't understand it. I've never
met anyone like that.  who could do this
correctly this transmission line is
incredible I'm
not saying this through my
loyalty Just if you know how to
repair a car The car will
go if you don't know how to
repair I've seen it thousands of times don't
ask about Lama at the
airport if they understand That's it if
they can explain it correctly then
yes they are good
people
otherwise you can't see emptiness in a
straight line you will suffer and you will die
it's your choice everything is not Sorry this is
how it is
And everything else is
very they are all very nice I
spend time with them but they can't teach you this
And you need this to see
emptiness directly you need it If you
don't learn this you won't be
able to I must
say trust yours
trust someone who can
repair I'm not
saying this because I don't know other
dealers
who don't know how to unmount
I'm a little ear in
time they are not a body
and something else let's try to
understand this we the real word here in
Sanskrit is skanda Repeat
skanda one of the five parts of you
skanda one of the five parts of you your
parts I  I translated skanda here
as body and mind in English we don't
say
di you made of five
skandas we say that you are body and mind
we say it like that in English We do
n't have in English it
means that to know
one of your
parts in normal language body and
mind who are you You are a connection the unification of body
and mind is normal in
Buddhism We never say just
body and mind
you we say you are yours Five skandas
is an ancient word that
means a mountain a
big pile of something a
pile of
something What did
your bedroom look like before
you left for the
airport a pile a pile of everything some of it
got into my my travel bag the
rest of the pile remained there mountains of
things
Buddhism We in English say
mountains of things five mountains of all sorts of things we don't
say uh five
wash five skandas But if you want to
say this to an English-speaking person and you are
five and you are your five piles
with I washed I cleaned my room
uh Here I translated it as body and mind
I want to
explain why I didn't use
these particular words because  you can't
understand Nagar If you don't
understand what he's saying, what you're not,
he's saying that you're not
your body and mind, and Buddha too.
Medicine Buddhas are not your body,
and we're connecting now, as it were, marrying Nagar
and medicine bu, and we'll have a big
[music]
ceremony, a pud, a fire pud.
When we make a
fire offering, we're connecting these two
books. Nagana explains what Buddhas are made of, what
if you don't know what
they're made of, you don't know how to
turn to them to help someone.
What medicine bu helped such a
sick person, you don't know who they are.
Where are they? If you don't understand this,
most likely, it won't work. If you understand
who they are, then the prayers will work. If you do
n't understand, it may not work.
Understood. If you understand how a
car works, maybe you can
fix it. If not, I suggest
giving this car to someone else. Who
knows how to
fix it? I had an experience. I broke my
teacher's car. It's a special feeling when
you break your teacher's car. I'll
never forget
him. He never asked me again.
repair the car I think that
was the real goal that I had in
mind
So
next next
Rafa
can you show this Imu can you show this
woman with a brain
we now You know we
have fun with artificial
intelligence my computer
specializes
how it
looks like ilo
intelligence SU there are still a lot of
strange things going on This is
artificial intelligence My wife finally
said Stop
calling me how about showing What
funny mistakes artificial
intelligence makes she's in the kitchen Come here you
need to see this she said I
will no longer look
at the mistakes that artificial
intelligence makes But this is a good picture of
artificial intelligence
if ordinary intelligence in
English we say body and mind
Why why do we say that these are all
things a pile of things mountains of things Why is carbon
so say Why are Buddhas Why are copper lumps not
piles of
things
they are neither one nor the
other Why did he say so a pile of things
mountains of
things I want to teach you that Why do we
say this in Buddhism and we don't say
body and mind this is a very famous
question we get the answer in adar ko
which NDU wrote
that
there is a
stanza in adar ko  Why do we talk
about five heaps of things there? Why don't we talk about
the hotel?
He says that there is a body and a mind. It
must be divided into the part that we call the
mind. You can say body and
mind. The main argument is
that they are not a body either, but it is very
important to divide the mind into the part that we
call the mind. The question is
why does everything lead to all
the problems that you have? There are
parts of your mind that
lead to mortality. They lead to death.
The fact that you can die is because of this.
It is a consequence of the work of
some parts of your
mind. Some parts of your mind can
kill you. I will repeat once again. We talk about
body and mind.
Yes, we call it body and mind. No, what do we call it
body
and mind? Which includes those parts that will
kill you. Every time we talk about
you in your body and in your mind. We want to
remind you that there is a
time bomb there that
can kill you. You are a homeless
person. You don't have to die.
We never say body. We say
body and mind. Which include those parts
that will kill you. Perhaps people will think.
Maybe you should get rid of these parts. Yes, yes, that's
why we don't say that. We
say body and some parts. Every
time we talk.  about your
parts
Rome, about your body and mind we will not
talk about the body and mind we will talk
about the body and mind which include parts
that will kill you
and We hope that you will someday
say it would be good to get rid of
these parts I don't know That's probably
why he demanded that we not talk about the
body and mind which include parts that will
kill you We don't have
this We don't have such a body and mind it
should represent this picture of body and
mind when I asked artificial
intelligence to show body and mind they
showed this I don't know what's in her
head
this is the result of the work of
artificial intelligence these are parts Let's talk about them
this is the next stanza
ready
adar
makosha very well known Why do we
separate among all mental functions
how many of them
50 51 or 46 or 52
depending on the school From what
source do we get information
So all mental functions Why do we
separate two parts of your mind that
lead to problems Why do we separate two
parts of the mind from
soshe mental functions the
psychology booth is very duck
psychology
written much better psychology than
modern they say Two functions out of
all and the
problematic ones are  problematic they
lead you to death If you can
repair and fix them then you don't have to
die Here they are of all the
mental functions Let's separate
the feelings and your ability to feel
and your
ability to
distinguish
these are two of the 46
or 46 of Buddhist
psychology this is a mental
function sometimes we feel through the body
but everything
but feeling the ability to
feel can be divided into or p
feelings what
way bad
feeling neutral can be divided
good bad can be divided
mental physical You can say
What physical feelings What
mental bad good mental
physical
and li also this
[music]
so ure so it should be
about When you are not sure
that you don't know whether it is good or bad
you often don't think about your
feelings If you feel that you are
too hot you feel it if you are
too cold
Feeling the temperature is average this
feeling we neutral feelings do not
divide into two parts we do not worry
about
it the ability to
feel is one of the parts of
your mind which is problematic the
ability to feel one of
46 leads to problems the second ability to
discriminate
is to evaluate bad good
roll this is too cold this  NVI is
not Ravi's ability.
This is the second mental function,
which in
Sanskrit is rama,
meaning there is such a step-by-step process
so that these two mental functions
lead to problems.
These two mental problems are the functions of
all the mental functions in your mind.
So, these two create all the problems.
Why does he say krama is a step-by-step
process, that
they are the root of the conflict and they
are the cause of samsara, the root of all
conflicts, and it's very simple,
and
human conflicts arise
because of what we say. This
creates the feeling that I feel good from this,
I feel bad, not this person I like
more, I like this. And this
person is related to my country. And this
person belongs to your country. This is how
we
discriminate. The root of the problem is this is
about feeling. I like people
who eat the same food as me, and they who have the
same skin as me, and I
don't like those who have these two
habits. An assessment based on feelings is the
root of all conflicts. This is all
Loy
ka
otka. Talk about yourself like this. Let's
agree. As I say, Ka  What are your
parts?
Include repeating every day instead of arguing about body
and
mind and you will see something that is
different. A different
face, different hair, no hair. Perhaps
if we don't call ourselves body and
mind for the rest of our lives, I will call you
three good
parts. Be careful with your
preferences. What do you like? What don't you like?
It's very difficult. It wouldn't be
part of Adar Koshi if we didn't do
this. We do all this. We all judge
other people. We
judge by
country, food, language. We do all this,
so he says. Let's remind ourselves
every time we talk about the body, mind.
Buda said, I don't want people to talk about the
body, mind, I want people to talk about the five
parts of myself. Two of them are problems for you.
Now, when you
call, translate this lesson. And when
you translate poetry.
I especially translated it for this
Sanskrit text into English.
I am for parents. We will have one
such lesson here for Parents, conscious
parenting, spiritual parenting during the
bu. I translated it for that lesson
because this lesson is based on poetry,
like for good parents, based on
world poetry. This is a cool concept.  It
seems to me that we will teach you how to be
good parents based on the
fact that a person who has never
been a parent will teach this
lesson. It was
not my idea, but I agreed with it. A
new question for you
now. Why is
Nagan in this section to
discuss
why he didn't take someone else? Why did he
choose Buddha for this
discussion? Why didn't he say all living
beings are made from the body and mind and they
are their body and mind in this way? What do
you think about this? Why didn't he
say this? Why did he choose
Buddhas? The body and mind of
Buddhas, we
think, are self-
existent. Here is the answer. Here is the
answer. A very deep answer and it is
complex. Buddhas are made from the body and
mind.
Medicine Buddhas are also made from the body and
mind. It would not be
necessary. If there was a pen, I
can
borrow it. I just like the
pen. The body and mind. Yes,
Buddhas are
made of the mind. In school,
the gift has different parts and from them we
bring you talk about
them in unlimited form
and how they became Buddhas. Were they bodies and minds?
Yes,
Buddhas are made from their body and
mind. Ordinary people are also made from the body and
mind. He doesn't talk about ordinary people in this
section. He talks about hathas.
budah about those who have gone so far,
you can say
yes He is not talking about ordinary people,
but you have a body and mind
before you become a Buddha and do you
still have a body? How do you
become a Buddha before
that? You are your body and
mind. This is the lid and the base of the
pen. This is the lid of the pen and the
pen. I will tell you when you teach this. These are things. These are
things. It says
No, let me draw you a beard now.
You are like, no, come on.
Someone
says to me, the pen
and the lid are together and I say, this is not a
pen. They say, come here, I will
draw you a beard now. No, no, don't
draw it. Come on, it's practically
Halloween
soon. Do you believe then that this is a pen?
Then don't say that you don't believe that this is a
pen. You don't want me to draw you a
mustache and beard.
Tim, the
object was only one person who allowed
me to draw. It was a man in Florida who allowed me to draw. A
pen and a
lid are a pen, the lid and the base are the
base of a pen. It is not a chew
toy.
Yes,
we didn't say that. It is a
pen for whom, for whom. Now you have already
changed a little.  your answers howl for
whom are you
ready and mind Buddha is a body and mind for
whom Let's be
ready again Buddhas are their body and mind And you
ask for whom is this the correct
answer Say yes to
say that they are so or no is the
wrong
answer By the way, in the
debate on
this question Maybe it can be
misunderstood then you need to ask for
clarification to the question If the question is very
tricky it can be
answered in different ways you can lose as a
defender If you don't Ask for
clarification the body of the Buddha is a body and mind for
whom
WH
in If you didn't
clarify the debate because both Answers are
correct no and yes are the correct
answers the lid and base are the
handle for whom if you say yes you are
mistaken if you say no you are mistaken it is
clear this is the
key to the books of the
Buddha's garnahs this is their body and mind for whom does this
say something about what does this tell us for
dollars tells us something about the
process if we say that they are not
boomers then they become
boomers I'll drink orange
juice for now you are
right
today ngi this
comes from the beholder
perceiver for whom Buddhas have a
body and  mind they are body mind for
whom
for a person who has seeds
to see
Will they be like this it is
clear they themselves for themselves they
[music]
buds this refers to people who are not yet
Buddha for whom for whom is that person
who is not a Buddha for whom he
is
Budo is the one who is not a
Buddha is the nihilation of body and mind This was a
question question and you must say for
whom if you see a person in this body
and mind it comes from your seeds from
you also a
pen Let's go back to the verse
he body is a
body of
media help they are their body yes
or no for
whom we can say
no because we are talking for no one and
are not something other than a body Maybe
they are a stone or plants for
whom there are many cases of people who people
who met Buddha as a tree as a
bridge as the
earth
they correctly
Saw Saw their children as
bu is Buddha's body my we can
say No are they something other
than a body We cannot
say yet They have a body and a
mind we do not
know we cannot
say yet the second part here is
called these are questions of initial
data questions of initial data that  This is
for the initial data for the raw data if
literally there is this
pen for whom this pen for whom this
black cylinder is a white cylinder so for
whom we need to constantly repeat for
whom even parts of the higher school of Buddhism
Who invented the higher school of
Buddhism
Nagan traditionally we speak on
garna the highest teaching of
emptiness the founder of Nagan is considered
the founder if Buddha has a body and
mind says that they do not have
bodies the initial data
depends on who is
looking it is not the pen cap itself it is not the
base of the pen they
together are not a pen It's easy I got it a
dog I
understand this but does a dog see a black cylinder
and a person also sees a black white
cylinder And what about a
blind
person even white color even black
color
even raw
data of human experience comes from
you you you see there the cap and the base of the
pen you see black and
white
mental buds
it shi on the pen cap and on the base of the
pen you are there You will not find a pen separately
it can be a
pen Yes if a person has seeds
to see a pen and draw a beard with this
pen Yes you can see it as a pen of
your own side  no, otherwise
the dog wouldn't play
How do you like this poem Does
it make sense Buddhas are body and mind I don't know
yet give me more information they
are something else other than body and mind
Maybe
they have body and mind I don't know it
depends on who is looking many people can't
see their children as
if someone told
me the heart is a dog
I answered if you see it that way then it's
normal it's really normal
If he sees it that way then why not they don't have a
body mind they are not inside their
body mind everything is clear for now Yes Wow Let's
move on to the
last one so those who have gone they have neither
body nor mind it's true they have a body and
mind of course they have m I didn't say that
they don't only said that
they don't have a body ma I
said that those who have gone so far have gone so far
that they don't have a body ma in their
perception I didn't say that they don't have they have
for themselves they see themselves with a body
mind it's a pen This is the whole question about the pen
remember the pen Where are the
Buddhas Where are the Buddhas of medicine When you
invite them You  you invite from your mind
when you invite the Buddha of medicine to
come and negotiate so that your
uncle's cancer goes away where do they come from they
come from you they
come from you if the Buddha comes from you
it means that they can't work they do
n't work
no It's the other way around by the way the only
way they can work is when they
come from me
Wait you're not Buddha and you create the
Buddha No no problem I have hot
seeds today cool seeds
Today you are not a Buddha but you can create the
Buddha no problem I am not a Buddha but I
have
seeds there I laid out all the
chairs they come from
you you created
them can they do for you those things
that you can't do for yourself Yes
it's very beautiful You are well taught by
someone I am very grateful to your
teachers
we had five students
in
1993 when we started 30 years ago By the way
we will have our thirtieth anniversary in
Kyoto We have five we had
five
students
and 200,000
now DCI
150,000 people
DCI I'll tell you today
590 with a tail unread
had
572 everyone is writing emails that I haven't
answered yet main can I ask you a question but there
are still 200,000 others who have
questions I feel such disappointment
such
exhaustion upset it hurts me that
people don't
understand consider you an
engineer You have fuss he has
200,000
multiply just 5 minutes they say everyone everyone
says not only 5 minutes of the
body it's a million mi minutes divide
by
17,000 hours if I give everyone 5 minutes I carry
my whole life spent to create these
200,000 people I'm happy I feel a
lot of happiness from
this It took 50 years to create
200,000 students But I don't have time
to talk to everyone for 5 minutes it's
almost impossible I would just die it
would
kill me list of very qualified
teachers you Ask them about something and them and
me I guarantee you will get exactly the
same
answer do you think that I
more this is
true Besides that I taught some of them
I taught for 30 years if they give me such an
answer I will
fire them I am not saying that I do not
enjoy I like communicating with
people I love growing up with a big family I
like people communicating with people I am not
saying don't stop questions yes
keep
trying if I start to be so
irritated then you will understand Why is there a
list of people here who can give
you the same answer Rebecca can you
stand up she was my student since she was a teenager
she still looks like a
teenager
I am
kidding How old were you when you
started with me 21
years old in college then studied in New York New
York and please stand up you
[applause]
saw 2530 years with me for
years 25 years was my personal assistant
assistant Thank you for
[applause]
that's 27 years together with
if she does not give the same answer as me I
[applause] I
will fire her sko years
27 by the way he does a
lot too like  assistant now this is already a
lot
for in there were students now
200,000 I expand my my potential by
100% if m needed they both can
help Look for my
[applause]
sunam shch
child 13 years old just
cooler than others a little
re he can give an answer the same as but
after 13
years all these people They are wonderful
teachers Stand up
[applause]
please Reno 15
years old my
[applause]
ka 20 years
wow I remember I just got out of a three-year
retreat walking through the
desert then by and I asked She said
yes I told her I have a job for
you
yes you had you had a job
[music]
Yes How many years
26 I can't teach a course for
parents
[applause] and
heard how many
years and
[applause]
beat Count your
years together 23 years
bi
together 33
[applause]
years Angeli
hello 18 years old
it seems
the ear can hear they are all studying Paradise studied
studying the diamond path this is a secret
teaching
after I completed all the
courses 18 courses and then I had to go to the
Ayanami courses and go through each page of
training many hours of years
this is 30,000 pages of translation This is the
best course of Paradise in the history of the last
2000 years I am sure of this I believe in
this you
need you can ask them questions about the
diamond path Diamond
path I did not allow them to start this
training until they completed 18
courses I only searched for a few people
where there were smart and beautiful I
told them that I decided that they did not need to take the basic
courses
and
they had real
failures they failed I don’t
do this anymore I make sure that my students finish
and then move on to Dasha this will be a
problem for you If you don’t
do this At first I said that one and
one person whose name I
will not be he knew all the answers to all 18
courses and he found me on  one day off And
for this of course He should be
praised because you know This is 30,000
pages of text in any case
it was created this whole program to
take 6-7
years if you want it faster
Study it I don't mind I think that you can do it
4-5 years if you work very hard
but part of the idea is to take
these so that it takes 7 years so that you
mature so that you become more mature Your
thinking has become The past mature and you become
older So that you have more
life experience so that you
transform in these 7 years will I
teach you or not 7 years you Change the
truth you will grow up you sing I must
say that these 18 20 30
years were not like this when they They
changed all these people it was a long
It was a long hard
process it takes time of course to
answer all the
tests and homework You are only
deceiving
yourself you will not have a good experience with the
diamond
path You can relax these are the best
courses in history do not rush
through them if the homework is long
just relax and  do it and
enjoy it and don't think that I'm trying to I
don't know that I'm trying to somehow deceive you
don't deceive
yourself everyone is in a hurry to get to the level of Paradise
then they do homework when they
get to they say in the World Cup there is a problem and they
fail do it more and more
consciously gradually after all This must
be the experience of 14 years of study
you study for the first 14 years or
not you All the same
you for these 14
years this is my
experience These
people they have experience they invested this time
for each of
them for each of them we can say
that
there are or which are not with me now
You can ask them a question and they will
answer how I taught them I
know well Where are we now what we are
doing 5 minutes left I can sleep a little maybe
questions from the audience from the
online
group
200,000
students it is
impossible to do now What I did
10 or 20 years
ago please admit It's not that
I'm evil or I don't want to talk to this is
honest it's the
truth I really love
people people who know me know that  I
love people physically I can't
do this
next I'm the stupidest person in this
room I'm a very new person here everyone
else is
smart I don't understand the
pen
[music]
I've been listening to it for a whole year I'm confused I'm
confused with this story about the pen my
Semina This is my
stupidity I honestly don't understand about the pen
Let's make a pen very quickly
If I understood correctly I've
been trying to understand the story about the pen for a whole year but I don't
understand when I
come
it's a
white
feather I chose a pen because the logic is
that everyone has a pen in their
bag but that was before the mobile
phone but mobile phones don't
work that well because dogs are
n't
interested in them I'll still stick to the
story about the
pen Come on
This is not a stupid
example this is not
philosophy this is just the truth Yes, as it is
when a dog looks at this and doesn't
see a
pen this is a small philosophical thought
if they look at this they see a
chew toy and a person sees a
pen who is
right and this
proves that these things come from nothing
if a dog looks at a chew toy
if the pen came from itself well a
person would see a chew toy
too
by the way
logic we can't argue with it
she was alone  What in Florida who
argued with me And so I have never seen
anyone who would disagree with me
It looks like a pen for a person Yes, it looks
like a chew toy for a
puppy Yes, they are right Yes, and they are right through the
functionality a person can write and a dog
can chew a
game is
not a chew toy really
for dogs And for a person a pen I will
say this 100
times this should happen on its
part
Probably this should happen
from because the dog does not see the
pen
Please, please understand one
thing This must be the truth This is not me This is
not philosophy This is not Buddhism This is not Buddhism
This is just the
truth A dog sees a chew toy
A person sees a
pen A chew toy and a
pen must come from a dog or
from a living thing It is very simple A
pen does not exist on its own
When a dog sees a pen too A dog
does not see a pen This means the pen does not come
from the
pen It is not
lynching The same thing They want to live
this
object Sing
Sing
and a living being sees a pen This means the whole
world comes from us from
me You cannot deny this There is no
argument in any language There is no
philosophy Nothing that you can say
You cannot prove
this Come
from
so the whole thing comes from
you it must come from you
be careful When you
speak I ask when I ask does
this pen come from you because
when you speak like that
every idiot I met
came from
me every dictator
murderer you
produce
nuclear missiles they all came from the
same place from
you Uh you
want to solve this There is one way
how this can be all Allow this is already
Buddhism pen - This is
Buddhism no other Buddhism is
needed in the World Cup the point is you can't
blame anyone for anything if the pen the story
about the pen
logically it's true you can't
blame anyone else either in the World Cup or in the World Cup all this is
your fault
but every good thing also comes from
you yes I am the most beautiful person
met And have you seen what a beautiful sunset
Sunrise to see this sunrise
but you created all the beauty in the world every
beautiful person your Buddha you
created all
the happiness You gave birth to all the people in
this world including my granddaughter a lot of
joy
too if
the pen comes from
you
listen no one can
prove the
opposite no one can prove
that it doesn't come from you it's
you The only one  Who can do this? You are the
only one. Stop blaming
other people. I bark, which means I
shouldn't stop a bad person when
he tries to kill someone. I didn't
say that. If a bad person tries to
kill someone, and they come from your
seeds, and it will take 10 years to get up
and let them. No, well.
Try not to hurt anyone else because there are more
weapons. You can.
You must stop. You must
do something. If there are people who are running
away because there are bombs flying somewhere,
then you need to help them and ask your
friends to pay for it.
That's all Tim,
yeah.